audiomack.com 2018-12-24

# Privacy Policy on Audiomack

Effective as of February 10, 2016

This Privacy Policy explains how Audiomack, a music service and mobile app owned and operated by Audiomack Inc., collects, uses, and manages your personal data. By using the Platform (defined below) and/or by registering for a user account, you consent to our Privacy Policy, so it’s important you read it carefully. If you do not agree to any term, provision, or concept in this Privacy Policy, you should not use the Audiomack website, mobile website, mobile apps services or platform. Please contact [support@audiomack.com](mailto:support@audiomack.com) with any privacy-related questions.

Note: this Privacy Policy only applies to the Audiomack website, app, and any additional music delivery mechanism or platform hereafter developed and/or utilized in any way, shape or form by Audiomack Inc. (collectively hereby referred to as the “Platform”), When using the Platform you may encounter links or ads for other services, platforms, apps, and/or websites that are not a part of the Services. Audiomack assumes no responsibility for the privacy policies or activities of such third parties, and users should be sure to check the privacy policy of any third party site or platform they use.

## 1 - Introduction/Overview

Our Privacy Policy will provide you with a detailed explanation of how we collect and use your data on the Platform. Before we delve into the details, however, we’d like to provide you with a brief overview of our philosophy as it pertains to user privacy and to highlight some key basic ideas.

By using the Platform, you consent to the collection of certain types of data (outlined below). You should fully understand what we do (and don’t do) with your personal information and data.

We’d also like to offer a brief overview of what you’re consenting to by using the Platform. All of these points will be explained in more detail below.

By using the Platform, you consent to;

Our use of cookies and other related technologies;

The transfer of your information to a 3rd party outside of the country you reside in;

The collection, processing, use, and sharing of your information;

The public availability of certain kinds of personal information you elect to share by registering for an account, and your controls for sharing such information.

## 2 - Information we collect about you

Visiting and using the Platform does not require you to provide any personal information, however, by electing to register for a user account you will provide us with certain information as you complete the registration process:

 **Opt-In/Registration Data:**

To register for an Audiomack account, you must provide us with a valid email address. If you use Social Login (e.g. Facebook) to sign up, we will receive the email address you have registered with Facebook. You may _elect_ to provide us with certain other personal information - personal/artist biography, hometown, and links to your profiles on other social media platforms (Facebook, Twitter, etc).

We also collect and display the date of your initial user registration on your user profile as a month and year - e.g. August ‘14.

You will also provide certain personal data if you use our Contact Us tools, on-site forms, or send us an email regarding support, your account, or other topics.

You _may_ also provide other personal information through your use of the site and posting of audio material, in the track description, comments, or title fields.

 **Data we collect on usage, analytics, and cookies:**

By using the Platform, you consent to our use of different technologies and methods that collect information about how you use, access, and interact with the Platform, which may include any of the following;

Technical data such as your IP Address, geolocation, cookie data, URLs visited, mobile device ID and information, device attributes, operating system, network connection, browser type, language, and mobile app version.

Details of any searches you make using the Audiomack search tools, including the date and time searches were made.

Metrics concerning the duration, time, and frequency of your visits to and interactions with the Platform. Details of your subscription (if applicable), as well as information about your interactions with the Platform, specifically including but not limited to: plays, favorites, re-ups, playlist use, and interaction with other Audiomack members and/or artists.

Device sensor data including lat/long, geolocation, altitude, and measurements from your mobile device's gyroscope, GPS receivers, accelerometers, and other sensors.

Details of your interaction with any third-party apps, widgets, modals, and/or advertisements which are linked to or made available on the Platform.

Information about the website you visited immediately prior to your interaction with the Platform. Details of any content (music, song information, descriptions) you upload to the Platform.

Details concerning your interaction with any Platform methods of communication specifically including but not limited to emails and push/in-app notifications, such as whether you opened and/or clicked on such messages.

We may also obtain information about you from any 3rd party providers/partners and/or advertisers on the Platform which measure ad interaction.

## 3 - How we use your information

We may use your information for any of the following purposes;

To operate your Audiomack account, and to identify you when you use the Platform. Your email address and password are used for this identification;

To identify you and your actions (uploads, favorites, re-up’s, comments, etc) on the Platform; To provide technical functionality to the Platform; for research and development of new products, services, or functionality; and analyze your use of the Platform;

To provide you with technical support or assistance;

To communicate with you for marketing, support, and/or promotional purposes through email, text message, push, or in-app notifications;

To detect fraud or attempted manipulation of our charts, trending sections, or proprietary algorithms. Audiomack expressly reserves the right to remove any and all content from the Platform that Audiomack in its sole discretion reasonably believes is violating any copyright laws and/or is being used in any way, shape or form to manipulate any measurement system on the Platform (specifically including but not limited to any charts, trending sections, proprietary algorithms, play counts, favorites, re-up’s, download counts;

To provide you with advertising, features, information, links, messaging, or other content based on your geolocation and time of use;

To determine the location, orientation, and acceleration of a mobile device;

To ensure compliance with our Terms of Service (TOS), this Privacy Policy, or with any applicable state, local, federal, or international Copyright Law;

Information about your subscription tier (Gold, Platinum) if applicable;

To show you relevant ads on behalf of advertisers and/or sponsors, which may include location and sensor data, along with demographic data you make available to us or through connected third party services, recent search history, and behavior with content, ads, or other users on the Platform;

To provide you with a customized experience on the Platform.

## 4 - How we share your information

Information about you or your activity on the Platform may be shared in two ways: the first is information you share via your public profile on the Platform is publicly visible to other users of the Platform and thus is shared and the second is data and information Audiomack collects on you (as described in section two above) that Audiomack may in their sole discretion share with reputable third parties in hopes of enhancing the Platform, its analytics and services.

Information you share via your use of the Platform:

Any information you provide in your public profile (username, name, location, social media feeds) and/or use of the Platform (plays, favorites, following, re-ups, playlists) is public and may be seen by other users on the Platform or by Audiomack administrators.

Information we share:

Audiomack uses several reputable third party partners and services, based in the U.S., to enhance the functionality, reliability, utility, and profitability of the Platform and to provide certain specialized services for our administrators and users. Some examples of services Audiomack routinely works with are Localytics, Crashlytics, and other mobile analytics and data solutions. In order to work with said services, Audiomack will share certain user information, _but will only do so when necessary._ Although Audiomack is not responsible for the Privacy Policy or Data Security of said third party services, we emphasize data security and integrity as a top priority when selecting services to work with.

Audiomack uses aggregate and de-indentified user data to perform platform-scale analysis, optimizations, and advertisement targeting and retargeting. This data may be shared with third parties, but only once any personally identifiable information (email address, name) has been removed or hashed.

Audiomack will disclose your personal information in any case where it is necessary to do so to comply with a criminal complaint, subpoena, court order, or legitimate law enforcement inquiry.

Audiomack may disclose your personal information if we feel it is necessary to do so to protect our intellectual property, rights, business interests, or the safety or reliability of our platform, users, employees, or stakeholders.

Audiomack may transfer your information to any person or party that acquires all or a substantial portion of our company or assets, or in the case of a merger, acquisition, or if the company becomes insolvent.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads and collect information when you visit our website. These companies will NOT have access to or use any personally identifiable information (including your name, address, email address or telephone number) but will use other non-personal information about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements on this website, other sites, and other forms of media about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here: <http://networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp> or <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>.

## 5 - How we use cookies and technology

Audiomack uses cookies and related technology to enhance the Platform, provide you with a consistent experience, record login and registration information, and to serve you more relevant

advertisements. Some ads served by third parties may use limited information about you and your interaction with the Platform to enhance the targeting or retargeting of advertisements and marketing campaigns. You may refuse to accept cookies from the Audiomack and/or the Platform by declining the In-App/Desktop Notification policy that appeared to you the first time you viewed Audiomack’s App and/or Desktop Platform(s). At any time, in the event you would like to change your acceptance or refusal of cookies, please log out of your user account and log back in in, at which point the In-App Desktop Notification Policy will re-appear. Please be aware that you may not use the Platform without accepting cookies.

A cookie is a small file placed on your computer or mobile device when you visit a website which helps our site and our 3rd party advertising and data partners recognize your device the next time you visit the site. Cookies are essential for many simple functions such as recognizing a repeat visitor as logged in, and providing access to your account, favorites, playlists, and profile. Audiomack utilizes two common types of cookies - session based cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent cookies (which stay active until deleted or deactivate after a set period of time). Other technologies include pixel tags (transparent images which help us determine if a page or email has been viewed by a user), web beacons (also known as web bugs, which serve a similar function to pixel tags), and web storage. Additionally, mobile users may be tracked using Device ID and/or hashed data to identify repeat mobile usage. These combined technologies are used both by Audiomack and our 3rd party partners to ensure essential Platform functionality; target, serve, measure, and track advertising delivery, targeting, optimization, and performance; measure Platform analytics and usage; and to measure user and audience behavior, trends, demographics, and location.

Audiomack does not currently respond to or acknowledge Do Not Track (DNT) requests.

## 6 - Accessing and updating your information

You may update your personal information at any time by visiting your Dashboard page in your user profile. Please bear in mind that profile data that is updated may take a few hours or another reasonable period of time to update internally.

Your data will be deleted if you delete your account, however, please bear in mind that it may still show up on internet search engines for some time after deletion due to caching.

Please note, logging out of or deleting the mobile app from your device does not delete your user account.

 **FOR European Users:** Pursuant to Article 17 of the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”), in the event you withdraw your consent for Audiomack to collect data from you, you shall have the right to obtain from Audiomack the erasure of personal data concerning yourself without undue delay and Audiomack shall have the obligation to erase your personal data without undue delay.

In the event you elect to withdraw your consent for Audiomack to collect data from you, please email [privacy@audiomack.com](mailto:privacy@audiomack.com) from the email address associated with your account requesting that Audiomack erase any and all personal data concerning yourself. Once received, Audiomack shall process your request in the order it was received and shall erase your data without undue delay.

## 7 - Transfer to other countries/territories

Audiomack Inc. is based in the United States and follows all applicable U.S. laws concerning data storage and privacy. Although our third party providers and services are based in the United States, there may in some circumstances be cases where data is transmitted to servers outside of the U.S. as part of the normal operation of the Platform. Please be aware that not all countries have the same data storage and privacy laws as the United States, and by using the Audiomack Platform you consent to the storage, transfer, collection, and transmission of your data to other territories as necessary.

## 8 - Links

The Platform contains links to third-party content, advertisements, and sites that are not owned by nor affiliated with Audiomack Inc.. We cannot be held accountable for the content or privacy policy of third- party sites. Be sure to read their privacy policies to determine if you are comfortable with how they handle your information.

## 9 - Children

The Platform is not intended for use by those under the age of 13. We never knowingly or purposefully collect information from anyone under the age of 13, or under the legal age limit in their respective territory (“Age Limit”), under any circumstances. If you are under the Age Limit, you should not use the Platform and are expressly prohibited from registering for a user account, or transmitting any data or personal information on the Platform. If you are the parent/guardian of a child under the Age Limit and believe we have collected such information, please contact us immediately at [support@audiomack.com](mailto:support@audiomack.com) and it will be promptly removed.

## 10 - Changes to our Privacy Policy

We may, at our sole discretion, change the terms of this Privacy Policy at any time and for any reason. In the event that we do change this Privacy Policy, we will post notification of updates both within the Policy itself and via notifications throughout the Platform and specifically on the Audiomack website and mobile app. Please be sure to read all updates to the Privacy Policy thoroughly before continuing to use the Audiomack platform. Your continued use of the Platform constitutes acceptance of any new or changed terms in this Privacy Policy.

Please contact [support@audiomack.com](mailto:support@audiomack.com) with any questions or concerns about the Privacy Policy.
